Harka Bahadur Tamang

Developer Programmer

Torquay Road, 3216 Grovedale, Australia

(M) 0466073288 | (E) hbtamang69@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/harka-tamang-27b139173

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A committed and creative graduate with a solid educational background in Information Technology from University of New England. Skilled in multiple programming languages including HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, SQL, and Python and possess experience in customer service and teamwork. Willing to embrace additional training and development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, PHP, Java, JavaScript, Python

Framework Bootstrap, jQuery, React

Computer Systems: Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Android

Web Servers: Apache Web Server

Databases: MySQL, Microsoft Access

Computer Software: Microsoft Suite (Office, Excel, PowerPoint, Visio, Project), SharePoint,

WordPress, Adobe Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator

Version Control System: Git

API Rest API

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem solving and critical thinking.
- Strong Communication and Interpersonal Skills.
- Proactive, initiative and work well in team.
- Attention to detail.

ACADEMIC PROJECT

An Agricultural Sensor Data Collection and Logging System Mar 2019 - Nov 2019

Objective: to develop a system that collects data, cache them into the logger to read from the

sensors, sends them into the cloud database and perform web-based visualisation

eventually.

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Ajax, Apache Web Server, Arduino IDE, Google Cloud

platform (GCP), SQL

Duties: In a team of 2 people, I worked as project manager and micro-controller programmer. I

worked on the programming of micro-controller. Also, I was responsible for liaising

with the client.

Devices: • ESP32-WROOM-32D microcontroller development board

MLX90640 sensor

Outcome: Successfully created the system that collects the data through sensors and send it to

cloud database as per the requirements.

Result: Passed the project achieving Distinction.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Assistant

Liquorland Pty Ltd

May 2019 – Present

- Organized store shelf and displays to promote and maintain visually appealing environment.
- Offered each customer top-notch, personal service and polite support to boost sales and customer satisfaction.
- Assisted customer with prompt and polite support in store and via telephone with up-to-date knowledge of products and sales and store promotions.
- Used POS system to process sales, returns, online orders and gift card activations.

Packhouse Employee

Costa Group (Tomato)

March 2018 – Feb 2020

• Received tomato from glasshouses and stored them in the store-room/ packing-shed. Harka Bahadur Tamang

- Performed various tasks such as sorting, grading, weighing and packing tomato fruit.
- Helped prepare packages for dispatch by printing the package labels and labelling them.
- Performed general cleaning duties

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology

Graduated 2019

University of New England, Armidale 2350, NSW, Australia

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Graduated 2015

Institute of International Management Science, Putalisadak, Kathmandu, Nepal

Professional Year Program - Information Technology

Dec 2020 – Present

Australian Computer Society (ACS)

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

Australian Computer Society (ASC)

December 2020

REFERENCES

Available upon request.